{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. Which type of microorganisms can alter their metabolic activities based on the presence or absence of oxygen?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Aerobes",
        "b": "Obligate anaerobes",
        "c": "Facultative anaerobes",
        "d": "Microaerophiles"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. Halophiles are a broader category of which type of organisms?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Mesophiles",
        "b": "Extremophiles",
        "c": "Psychrophiles",
        "d": "Thermophiles"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""      
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. What is the main threat to microorganisms when they use oxygen for cellular respiration?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Excessive heat",
        "b": "Harmful superoxide and peroxides",
        "c": "Lack of nutrients",
        "d": "Low pH levels"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Which category of microorganisms prefers salt-free environments but can tolerate mild to moderate salt levels?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Slight halophiles",
        "b": "Moderate halophiles",
        "c": "Extreme halophiles",
        "d": "Halotolerant microrganisms"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""      
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. Which type of microorganism grows best at temperatures between 20 to 40 Â°C?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Psychrophiles",
        "b": "Mesophiles",
        "c": "Thermophiles",
        "d": "Extreme thermophiles"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Organisms that require a salt concentration of 15 to 30 percent for optimal growth are known as:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Slight halophiles",
        "b": "Moderate halophiles",
        "c": "Extreme halophiles",
        "d": "Halotolerant"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""      
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. You are a microbiologist working on cleaning up an oil spill in a polar region with extremely low temperatures. Which type of microorganism would be most suitable for this environment?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Mesophiles",
        "b": "Thermophiles",
        "c": "Psychrophiles",
        "d": "Extreme thermophiles"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Which type of microorganisms thrive in environments with a pH above 8.5?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Acidophiles",
        "b": "Neutrophils",
        "c": "Basophils (Alkalophiles)",
        "d": "Halophiles"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""      
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. At which wavelength is the absorbance of the E. coli culture is measured?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "450 nm",
        "b": "500 nm",
        "c": "600 nm",
        "d": "700 nm"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. Which pH range do neutrophils typically prefer for growth?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "1.0 - 3.0",
        "b": "5.5 - 8.5",
        "c": "8.5 - 10.5",
        "d": "4.0 - 5.0"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""      
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
